Guide to the J.V. (James Vincent) Cunningham Typescripts of poetry, 1931-1943
Department of Special Collections
J.V. (James Vincent) Cunningham Typescripts of poetry,
1931-1943
Special Collections Misc 424
Cunningham, J.V. (James Vincent), 1911-
2 folders
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Clayton I. Stafford, 1975.
Scope and Content
Includes 18 poems, most signed and dated, a reprint by from MODERN PHILOLOGY, "Logic and Lyric," 1953, and Charles Gullans' A BIBLIOGRAPHY OF THE PUBLISHED WORKS OF J.V. CUNNINGHAM, 1973.
Access Terms
Conley, John.; Gullans, Charles B.; Winters, Yvor, 1900-1968.; American literature--20th century.
Container List
- "Aeterne Rerum Conditor," nd (Folder 1)
  with autograph note on bottom
- "Clayton, forgive me...," nd (Folder 1)
- "Few men write poetry to their wives," nd (Folder 1)
- "Few men write poetry to their wives," variation in form (Folder 1)
- "High in the acacia sang...," nd (Folder 1)
- "Timor Dei," nd (Folder 1)
- "Valedictory, for Joanna Winters," nd (Folder 1)
- "Dogmatic Sestina," December 1931 (Folder 1)
- "Bookplate," 1933 (Folder 1)
- "Dedication for the Yearbook, for Don Stanford & Barbara F. Gibbs," 1933 (Folder 1)
- "Hic Iacet Cicada, Elegy on a cricket," 1933 (Folder 1)
- "Lector Aere Perenniorr, for Yvor Winters" 1933 (Folder 1)
- "The Beacon," 1934 (Folder 1)
- "The Chase," 1934 (Folder 1)
- "Epigrammata," 1933 with 1934 addition (Folder 1)
- "For Amaryllis," 1934 (Folder 1)
- "Meditations on a Memoir," 1943 (Folder 1)
- "The Operation of Alchemical and Devotional Metaphor in the Work of Francis Bacon," for Bacon Seminar, 1939, John Conley. 2 p., with autograph poem, "Summer Idyll," nd. by JVC (Folder 2)
- Logic and Lyric, by J.V. Cunningham, reprint from MODERN PHILOLOGY, 1953 (Folder 2)
- Gullans, Charles. A Bibliography of the Published Works of J.V. Cunningham, UCLA Library, 1973 (Folder 2)